Guide to the New York University Collection of Contemporary Composers' Websites MSS.496
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Grimes, Rachel, April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  The website contains information about one of her most recent works titled The Way Forth, a discography, a section of embedded video files, PDFs with sheet music for purchase, a news section, a calendar of events, and a biography of the artist. Capture of the site began in April 2014. This description was updated in March 2025.
  Rachel Grimes (b. 1970) is a Kentucky-based touring pianist; rock, and indie-rock group member; arranger; and composer of instrumental works for chamber and orchestral ensembles. She also creates music for film, multi-media installations, and collaborative live performances. Some of her more recent titles include The Blue Hour (2022), a Grammy-nominated work; The Way Forth (2019), a folk opera and film piece; and the soundtrack for The Doctor From India (2018). Grimes is also a board member of the African-American Genealogy Group of Kentucky, and is interested in the study of how genealogy and history research can lead to social change.
- Ha, Moon Young, April 2014-May 2015, March 2025-ongoing; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of moonyoung.net and sustainable-music.org in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Moon Young Ha (b. 1980) is a composer and artistic director based in New York City. He is the founder and director of the ensemble mise-en, through which he serves as a curator and conductor of contemporary classical music. Ha's pieces combine acoustics, electronics, video, and choreography with influences of jazz, pop, western, and non-western music styles.
  http://www.moonyoung.net/ was initially crawled in 2014-2015. The website contained a biography, a list of performances, a list of works, media, information about his ensemble, and contact information. In 2025, crawling resumed at https://www.sustainable-music.org/. The new website contains descriptions and videos of her projects and teaching materials.
- Haber, Yotam, August 2011- ongoing; Haber, Yotam, 1976-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of http://www.yotamhaber.com/ in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist, his CV, a calendar of his events, press pieces written about Haber, information about his compositions, and examples of his music in the form of embedded audio files. Capture of the site began in February 2014. This description is based on the October 2017 capture of the site.
  Embedded audio files do not function on the live site or in the capture.
  Yotam Haber (b. 1976) is a pianist and composer of classically-inspired instrumental chamber pieces. He was born in the Netherlands, and grew up in Israel and Milwaukee. His first monographic album of chamber music titled Torus, was released in 2015. He is also a Professor of Composition at the UMKC Conservatory and the Artistic Director Emeritus of MATA, a non-profit organization founded by Philip Glass.
- Hagen, Daron, February 2014-ongoing; Hagen, Daron, 1961-; 4 websites in 4 archived websites
  The composer's website contains a biography of the artist; his CV; a press kit for download; a news section which includes a calendar of events; a blog; a list of interviews and lectures; a compilations of reviews about Hagen's work; a discography; professional portraits of the artist and images of Hagen with colleagues; and contact information. His web presence also includes the websites for his "operafilms" and staged productions, 9/10: Love Before the Fall, Orson Rehearsed, and Hide.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of daronhagen.com, 9-10operafilm.art, and orsonrehearsed.art in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Daron Hagen (b. 1961) is an American filmmaker, writer, and composer of art songs, song cycles, choral works, operas, symphonies, concerti, and chamber works. In his role as a filmmaker, Hagen writes and directs "operafilms," where he combines music and screenplays authored by him. Hagen also published a memoir in 2019 titled Duet with the Past.
- Hallman, Joseph, February 2014- ongoing; Hallman, Joseph, 1979-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of josephhallman.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; his discography of published albums; scores for his compositions; excerpts from articles and reviews written about Hallman; and examples of his compositions in the form of embedded audio files. The pieces featured on the site are of chamber music, classically-influenced instrumental compositions for ensembles, and solo performers.
  The "Listen" section of the site was crawled separately in an attempt to ensure better capture of the site.
  Embedded SoundCloud audio files were not captured.
  Joseph Hallman (b. 1979) is a contemporary composer based in Philadelphia, PA. His works include concertos and chamber music, which combine influences of classical, Renaissance, and popular music.
- Harrison, Michael, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5924; Harrison, Michael (Michael Allen); 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of michaelharrison.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was rescoped to also include Wix and Parastorage domains.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; press articles and quotes regarding his music; a discography; a list of compositions with embedded media; information about his collaborations with other artists; a photo gallery with images of Harrison; a calendar of past and upcoming events; and contact information.
  Michael Harrison (b. 1958) is a New York-based composer and pianist. His compositions are specialized in just intonations and Indian ragas, and blend the classical music traditions of North India and Europe. Harrison is the inventor of the "harmonic piano," a grand piano that plays 24 notes per octave. Some examples of Harrison's most recent works include Seven Sacred Names, Just Constellations, and Tone Room.
- Hartman, Jonathan, February 2015-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  The website contains information on his projects, music reels, news from the composer, his biography, and contact information.
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of hartmanmusic.com and jonathanhartman.net in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website was rescoped to include Reelcrafter domains.
  Jonathan Hartman is a composer of television and film. His work is influenced by film scores, jazz, blues, and 20th century minimalism. Hartman's compositions include science fiction and fantasy, as well as dramatic scores. He has extensively created musical compositions for Warhammer, a company that produces collectible fantasy miniatures.
- Hauschka, April 2014- ongoing; Hauschka (Musician); 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of hauschka-net.de in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Volker Bertelmann (b. 1966), also known as Hauschka, is a German experimental composer, producer, and pianist, best known for his works for prepared piano. His approach to composition is interdisciplinary, often exploring the tension between different musical styles and genres, including classical, dance, theater, and electronic music. Notable works by Hauschka include A Different Forest (2019), What If (2017), and Abandoned City (2014), and the original score he created for the film All Quiet on the Western Front, which received an Academy Award for Best Music.
  The website contains a biography, a list of works, information about current projects, a list of upcoming concerts, and contact information. This description is based on the January 2023 crawl.
- Hays, Gabriel, February 2015-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of gabrielhays.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Gabriel Hays is a Los Angeles-based composer of film, television, multimedia, orchestra, band, and chamber music. Works by Hays include the music for Netflix's original film Secret Magic Control Agency, released in 2021; Disney projects such as Star Wars: Galactic Pals; and the PBS television release Half the Sky.
  The website features a biography, a list of works, videos, selected audio, studio photos, and contact information.
- Hearne, Ted, February 2015- ongoing; Hearne, Ted, 1982-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of tedhearne.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Embedded images, video and SoundCloud audio files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.
  Ted Hearne (b. 1982) is a composer, singer, bandleader and recording artist. His works focus on unconventional interactions between text and music. Notable works by Hearne include Sound From the Bench and Place, both of which were finalists for the Pulitzer Prize in 2018 and 2021. Other titles by Hearne include The Source, Katrina Ballads, and Law of Mosaics. Hearne also participates in collaborative musical projects such as the vocal-electronic duo R WE WHO R WE with Philip White.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; news; a list of press features and interviews; information about Hearne's projects; information about his music with embedded video and audio files; a discography; a calendar of events; and contact information.
- Hemingway, Gerry, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5925; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of gerryhemingway.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; a list of his works; news regarding his work; a discography; press articles; videos of his performances; audio files; a list upcoming and recent performances; links and articles of interest; information about his recordings; and contact information.
  Gerry Hemingway (b. 1955) is a percussionist, composer, soloist, collaborator, ensemble member, and educator. In the 1970s he played with artists such as Anthony Davis, Wadada Leo Smith, George Lewis and Anthony Braxton. During this time, he was also a member of the collective trio BassDrumBone. From 1983-1994, Hemingway was also part of the Anthony Braxton quartet and has participated in multiple other collaborations and musical groups such as GRH Trio and WHO Trio. His repertoire ranges from solo to quintet music.
- Hernandez, Katt, February 2014-ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of katthernandez.com and sites.google.com/site/katthernandez/home in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Katt Hernandez (b. 1974) is a composer, improviser, violinist, producer, and artistic researcher based in Stockholm, Sweden. Since relocating to Stockholm from the United States in 2010, she has worked as a solo violinist and in collaboration with multiple musicians across Europe. She is also the co-founder of The Schematics and Deuterium Quartet.
  The website contains a biography, contact information, links, news, photos, audio, video, a list of upcoming performances, recordings, teaching information, and a list of compositions.
- Hersch, Michael, June 2017-ongoing; cuid5926; Hersch, Michael, 1971-; 3 websites in 3 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of michaelhersch.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the composer's website includes news about the artist; a biography; a list of projects accompanied by video files; a selection of concerts; a list of works; a section of embedded audio and video files with examples and live performances of his works; a discography; press features; and contact information. His web presence also includes the websites for Michael Hersch's works, I hope we get a chance to visit soon and the script of storms.
  Michael Hersch (b. 1971) is a composer and pianist. His compositions include large ensemble, soloist, chamber, opera, cantata, and vocal music. Recent premieres of Hersch's work include his Violin Concerto, his piece On the Threshold of Winter, and his 10-hour chamber cycle titled sew me into a shroud of leaves. Other examples of notable works by Hersch include Domicilium, along the ravines, and end stages.
- Higdon, Jennifer, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5927; Higdon, Jennifer, 1962-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of jenniferhigdon.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The artist's website contains a biography; a list of her works and recordings; reviews of her work; information on upcoming performances; and contact information.
  Jennifer Higdon (b. 1962) is a composer of contemporary classical music whose works include orchestral, chamber, choral, vocal, opera, and wind ensemble. Higdon has been a recipient of the Pulitzer Prize in music and three Grammy Awards for Best Contemporary Classical Compositions. Higdon's concertos are among her most acclaimed works. Examples of these pieces include her Violin Concerto, Percussion Concerto, Viola Concerto, and Harp Concerto.
- Hoffman, Elizabeth, November 2017- ongoing; Hoffman, Elizabeth, 1961-; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of wp.nyu.edu/elizabeth_hoffman in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains a biography of the artist; a calendar of her events; news about Hoffman; a list of selected articles by her; reviews and articles about Hoffman and her works; information about her published music; a list of her works that includes percussion, electroacoustic, music, ensemble, solo orchestra and opera music; images of the artist; information about her teaching and research; her CV; and information about her sound installation located inside Bobst Library.
  Elizabeth Hoffman (b. 1961) is a New York City-based composer of pieces for opera, orchestra, solo, and ensemble performances created through both acoustic and computer-driven media. Hoffman compositional interests include micro-timbre, texture, tuning, and spatialization. In 2019, Hoffman created a permanent sound installation located inside the atrium of New York University's Bobst Library. The piece is titled RETU(R)NINGS, and sounds daily for 1 to 2 minutes at sunset. She is also a Professor of Music at NYU.
- Holcomb, Robin, June 2017- ongoing; cuid5929; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of robinholcomb.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the composer's website includes a biography of Holcomb accompanied by a selection of quotes about her work by the press, information about her work with embedded audio files, a calendar of upcoming concerts, a gallery of portraits of the artist, and press kits.
  Robin Holcomb (b. 1954) is a pianist, composer, librettist, singer, and songwriter. She is a founder and co-director of The New York Composers Orchestra and The Washington Composers Orchestra (WACO). Examples of notable compositions by Holcomb include Paradise, No Thing Lives to Itself, We Are All Failing Them, and All the White.
- Holdman, James E., April 2014- ongoing; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of jamesholdman.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  James Holdman is a composer, performer, and improviser based in Minneapolis, MN. Holdman's compositions explore music of different cultures and styles, including post-tonal art music, jazz, and non-Western musical traditions. Holdman has performed with different groups including the Marimba Bullies, earWorm, Ammala Middle Eastern Music and Dance, Mandragora, Modal Operandi, The Dextet, and Head Octet, among others. His repertoire includes works such as Turncoat Hat (2021), Haunted House (2013), and Maddy's Eaten a Little Hummus Again (2008).
  The website features a biography, a calendar of events, a list of works, recordings, images, news, and contact information.
- Holzborn, Damon, April 2014-ongoing; 18 websites in 18 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of damonholzborn.com, rustle.works, tentacle.ink, llllllll.co, twitter.com, personalshout.com, and personalbayou.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The artist's website contains a biography, example of works by Holzborn in the form of embedded audio files accompanied by written descriptions; a discography; a section dedicated to the artist's projects in the realm of art which includes web and algorithmic pieces as well as games, Twitter bots, and installations; information about projects that he has coded; and his contact information.
  The crawls related to Holzborn also include Rustle Works, a software studio formed as a partnership between musician/developer Holzborn and writer/filmmaker Betsy Nagler. The studio combines technology, music, and storytelling to create tools, games, and art projects. The website for Rustle Works contains information and links to their projects. Projects include Twitter bots and art projects little words, with w/, Tap Hear, and Disting mk4 Quick Guide. little words is an internet game that was created by Holzborn in collaboration with Betsy Nagler. It is a word game with the goal to take a large word and make little words for points. Holzborn also created Personal Bayou and Personal Shout, two digital art installations with George Lewis. The captures also include the Exquisite Coasts, Quaxtrip, and Coast Express, which were projects created by Holzborn for musicians to play together remotely in response to the COVID-19 pandemic. Tentacle, created by Holzborn and Amir Hariri, is an algorithmic drawing project that creates gestural abstractions using contour drawing techniques. Reference of Ancient Times is a guide to Rumble of Ancient Times, an 8-bit noise synthesizer and sequencer.
  Damon Holzborn is a Brooklyn-based composer of computer music, often featuring electronic instruments and improvisation. He is also a new media artist and software developer. Works by Holzborn include algorithmic image and language projects; mobile games; music tools; and sound installation. In his musical compositions, Holzborn employs custom software in combination with traditional effects. He was a founding member of the experimental music group Trummerflora Collective (1999-2009) and a co-creator of Zu Casa (1997-2013), an online guide for experimental music.
- Honstein, Robert, February 2014- ongoing; cuid5891; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of roberthonstein.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The website contains news regarding his work, a biography of the artist, calendar of upcoming events, and a list of his works. It also includes information about his projects and embedded videos of his music, live performances, and score follow videos.
  Robert Honstein (b. 1980) is a New York-based composer of orchestral, chamber, vocal, and film music, with a background in piano and singing. He is a founding member of the composer collective Sleeping Giant and a co-founder of the music festival Fast Forward Austin, and the concert series Times Two, which was based in Boston and paired artists from diverse backgrounds. Honstein has also had a role as an educator of composition seminars and workshops, which includes serving as the Program Director of Concert Composition at NYU Steinhardt.
- Horvitz, Wayne, July 2017- ongoing; cuid5913; 1 websites in 1 archived website
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of waynehorvitz.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  As of April 2025, the website contains a biography of the artist; news; a list of his works and projects; a discography; writings and scores; information on his teachings; an online store; press features; contact information; and a calendar of his events.
  Wayne Horvitz (b. 1955) is a composer, pianist, and electronic musician who has performed around the world. Horvitz's works include pieces for theater, dance, film, and television. Horvitz leads multiple ensembles including The Snowghost Trio, Sweeter Than the Day, The Royal Room Collective Music Ensemble, Brooks/Horvitz/Kim, Electric Circus, and The Royal We. Examples of notable works authored by Horvitz include Joe Hill: 16 Actions for Chamber Orchestra and Soloist, Some Places Are Forever Afternoon, and Those Who Remain.
- Hough, Matthew, February 2014-ongoing; Hough, Matthew, 1981-; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of matthewhough.com and houghhousemusic.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  Crawls were also rescoped to include YouTube and SoundCloud embedded materials.
  Hough's professional website features a biography of the artist; news about upcoming releases and performances; a selection of the artist's work available for streaming with score; a full discography and catalog of compositions; a list of Hough's presentations; publications of his research; and information about his role as a Professor of Composition, Theory, and Performance. His web presence also includes the website for Hough House, Matthew Hough's music publishing company, through which he publishes and sells the scores for his compositions. As of April 2025, the publishing company's website no longer exists at this URL.
  Matthew Hough (b. 1981) is a composer, theorist, guitarist, and performer based in the San Francisco Bay area. Hough composes new and popular music for chamber ensemble, vocal ensemble, solo instrumentalists, and ensembles with variable instrumentation. His work also includes rearrangements of other composers' works for guitar. Hough's research on music theory has been published in Music Theory Online and was also presented at different institutions. He is also the co-founder of the chamber groups Zs, Seductive Sprigs, and Music=quals.
- Hron, Terri, November 2017-ongoing; 2 websites in 2 archived websites
  Robots.txt was ignored. Crawl was limited to domains and subdomains of birdonawire.ca and terrihron.com in order to remain within the collection scope and data constraints.
  The composer's website contains a biography of the artist; a portfolio of her works and projects accompanied by embedded audio and video files; a discography of her published albums; news about the artist; and contact information. The website http://www.birdonawire.ca/ no longer exists. The composer's website was moved to the URL http://terrihron.com.
  Embedded SoundCloud audio and Vimeo video files on the site were captured, but do not render in the archived copy. Future changes to the Wayback Machine may allow the files to be played.